I started to make sense of a lot of what
I've been doing over the last few years
I've done quite a lot of sort of deep
transformational practices a lot of
shadow work so integrating the shadow
and actually feeling that real sense of
becoming more in alignment with myself
but it was through listening to you that
I made this connection with the logos
with the idea that this is actually a
deep principle of Western culture which
gave it another it's it's the principle
of the Incarnation right because the
Incarnation is is as at least a symbolic
representation of the idea that the
Spirit has to fully inhabit the body
right and that's also a remarkable it's
a remarkable idea especially because the
spirit so to speak the psyche if you
want flees from the body and terror
because the body is the place of
mortality and suffering and so people
are disembodied and it's because what
one way of looking at is because they're
too afraid to become fully embodied and
it's no wonder they're afraid there's
reason to be afraid but the question is
well what would you be like if you had
the courage to be fully embodied and
that's fully incarnate that's another
way of thinking about that and the idea
that Christian idea is that the fully
incarnate human being is the Messiah
that's the idea that's a hell of an idea
you know but it means embracing the
horrors of the world that's what it
means and that's not only the horrors of
the world but the evil of the world you
know so there's this idea that Christ
absolutely well then those are those are
not different and you know there's this
idea that not only was Christ the
Incarnate spirit right so fully
descended into the body let's say but
that he also took the sins of the world
onto himself and what that means is that
psychologically speaking is that part of
spiritual development is to recognize
the satanic tendencies that characterize
you and to fully wrestle with them and
to and to integrate them that's the
thing it's it's not so much to cast them
away it's to transmute them you know and
you can see the difference between
people who've done that and people who
haven't at least to some degree because
people who haven't integrated the shadow
at all are naive and you can tell that
when you look at them and you can tell
that when you talk to them and because
they're naive they're often resentful as
well because they get taken advantage of
it and someone who's integrated that
more they're dangerous in in the martial
arts sort of way which is they're
dangerous but they don't have to be they
don't have to use it